The music that thrilled the world… and the killing that stunned it!
Gimme Shelter is a documentary, music film directed by Albert Maysles.
A detailed chronicle of the famous 1969 tour of the United States by the British rock band The Rolling Stones, which culminated with the disastrous and tragic concert held on December 6 at the
Altamont Speedway Free Festival, an event of historical significance, as it marked the end of an era: the generation of peace and love suddenly became the generation of disillusionment.
Self - The Rolling Stones Member, played by Mick Jagger.
Self - The Rolling Stones Member, played by Charlie Watts.
Self - The Rolling Stones Member, played by Keith Richards.
Self - The Rolling Stones Member, played by Mick Taylor.
Self - The Rolling Stones Member, played by Bill Wyman.
Self, played by Marty Balin.
Gimme Shelter is a 1970 American documentary film directed by Albert and David Maysles and Charlotte Zwerin chronicling the last weeks of
the Rolling Stones' 1969 US tour which culminated in the disastrous Altamont Free Concert and the killing of Meredith Hunter.
The film is named after "Gimme Shelter", the lead track
from the group's 1969 album Let It Bleed.
Gimme Shelter was screened out of competition as the
opening film of the 1971 Cannes Film Festival.
The film explores themes of hells angels, concert film,
rock concert, direct cinema, music tour.